There's a hundred
and four days of summer vacation
And school comes
along just to end it
So the annual
problem for our generation
Is finding a
good way to spend it
Like maybe…
Building a rocket
or fighting a mummy
Or climbing up
the Eiffel Tower
Discovering
something that doesn't exist
Hey，Giving a
monkey a shower
Serpent
tidal waves
Creating nanobots
and locating Frankenstein's brain
Said Josie
Finding a
dodo bird
Painting a
continent
Driving her
sister insane
Said Vika
As you can see
There's a whole lot of stuff to do before school starts this fall
Said Clarice
So stick with us
Cause Phineas and
Ferb are gonna do it all
媽媽，飛哥和小佛他們又開始喇
過山車
音樂劇，你知道小夫
暑假當中最好的一次時光
是打造過山車
我們應該再來一次
但是這次要有音樂劇的
感覺點啊？
我們做同樣的事
除了我們會不由
自主地在沒有音樂的情況下
載歌載舞，嗯
你點知道其他人也會跟
我們一起載歌載舞呢？
我不知道，我想他們可能會
那就夠喇，我加入
Cause when we're
back in school come next September
And they ask us
we can both remember
Every cool and
clever thing we did all summer long
And glancing back
we're gonna be so glad that we
Didn't sit all
day and watch TV
I don't think
anyone can disagree
The world is
possibilities
And that's
what makes me say
Hey fur
I know what we'
re gonna do today
Hey fur
I know what we'
re gonna do today
Hey fur
I know what we'
re gonna do today
Hey fur
I know what we'
re gonna do today
Hey fur
I know what we'
re gonna do today
Hey fur， hey fur
I know what we'
re gonna do today
Hey fur
I know what we'
re gonna do today
Hey fur
I know what we'
re gonna do today
Hey fur，Hey fur
I know what we'
re gonna do today
Hey fur
I know what we'
re gonna do today
Hey fur
I know what we'
re gonna do today
Hey fur
Hey fur，Hey fur
飛哥、小佛，我要去拿些東西
你們別惹麻煩，好嘛？
好的，媽
家裏我負責，對嘛？
你告訴他們我負責喇嘛？
放輕鬆，沒有誰要負責的
可是如果發生緊急事件呢？
比方説呢？
如果…
如果是一頭鹿或者
是一群鹿衝進屋子攻擊人呢？
如果真係噉，就由你負責，好
好啦，媽説我來負責，萬一有狀況的話
如果沒有路的話，條件就不成立了
是嗎？
你這麼説可真有意思，噢
我會看着你們
喂？
噢，嗨，史黛西，我媽剛出去
她讓我負責，萬一有狀況的話
那總比沒得管好
這只是授權程度嘅問題
有些支配有條件，然後就有基本的支配
你支配了大部分，然後就完全的支配
完全不需要修飾，那就是我所追求的
等等，我弟弟現在在做什麼？
「從你那看得到」到底什麼意思？
看見什麼？
小夫，我們可以從這裏看到史黛西的家
飛哥，這係什麼？
你喜歡咩？
我要去跟媽媽説，當她看到你做的好事
你就死定了
You're going down
when I get mom to see
You're going
down to the ground
That's ridiculous monstrosity
You'll never get
away with this again
In your G O
I N G D O W N
Going down
spread the news
from coast to coast
Going down
your operation exposed
I could say more
but I don't wanna boast
Going down
get used to butter
cause you're
both our toast
If a certain
condition arises
I'm the one to
avert the crisis
You think you'
re saving lives
but you forgot
that I'm the one in charge
Conditionally
You're going down
down，down，down
down
You're going down
看吧，自然就會有音樂
嗨，凱蒂絲，你們歌唱得怎麼樣啊？
很好，但還是很生氣，我想換我啦
What you doing？
What's today'
s activity？
What you doing？
By any chance
could it include me？
What you doing？
I don't
mean to disturb
What you doing？
You know it's not
really directed at her
When I say "What
you doing？"，"What you
What you doing？
Can I be part
of the show？
When I say
What you doing？
嗨，伊莎貝拉，你們在做什麼呢？
建造一個過山車，又一次，好酷啊，嗨
小佛
看起來你話還是很少啊，不，你錯過了
剛剛他説了兩句，嘩，話真多，嘿
泰瑞呢？
早安，密探阿泰
邪惡的杜芬舒斯又在玩老把戲喇
因為不明的理由
他買走了這國家八成的希伯
凱爾，他不是已經做過喇嘛？
是他，長官，暑假一開始
好吧，密探阿泰
出發去做你上回做過的事，祝你好運
密探阿泰
這世界的存亡就掌握在
密探和保鑣的希伯上面喇，不像我
我的世界就是這個陰幕
只是個長方形
但是我的…
開爾
抱歉，長官，我以為你唱完了
還需要再開燈嗎？
不算喇，我已經沒有靈感喇
所以，這樣我
懂了固態燃料推進火箭飛進停車位
然後，我們在螺旋軌道區域放蛇
我要去找一些蛇
媽媽，你現在就得回家
我來猜猜，有一隻鹿在我們家客廳裏
係一大群鹿
哦，反正是鹿就對喇
媽媽相信我是一群鹿
你要我拿字典給你看嗎？
你來就是要説這個嗎？
不是，你得看看飛哥和小佛在做啲事
他們在蓋過山車，愛迪絲
那個你已經用過喇，Mom， look
don't roll
your eyes at me
Mom， look
Just come
over and see
Mom，look
It shouldn'
t be so hard
Mom，look
They built it
in the backyard
But they made
it winter in June
Mom，look
Built a rocket to the moon
Mom
they caused me
so much pain，Mom
they even gave
me Perry's brain
Mom，they even
gave me Perry's brain
Oh，真是夠喇
They built a submarine
a time machine
a haunted house
that made me scream
Drove cattle
through the mall
Built a giant
bowling ball
Blow me up
to 50 feet
A cherry dragged
me down the street
Woo
Me their stupid
clothes and fashion craze
Shoelaces and
household faze
Shot me
through a circus tent
Always ask for
parry while a lava flow destroyed my feet
The giant
roller derby race
Thought I came
in at the vise
Built a roller
coaster twice
凱迪斯，説真的
飛哥要當過山車的設計師
也太年輕了吧？
哦，是…
是太年輕
Aren't you a little young to build a roller coaster？
是的…我是…
I must say that I'
m really quite impressed
But all your
permits are in order
Don't forget the
bricks and mortar
And if you need
a power loader
Be my guest
But if I'm pressed
I'd say you look
a little young to drive a fork
是的…我是…
It's good to see
a younger guy like you
Who's creative
and ambitious
A little bigger
than his britches
And who's got a
fresh exciting point of view
Yes
it's true that you seem a little young to do the things that you do
Even with all the
moxie you've got
Yes
you seem a little green to be controlling this machinery
Yeah
I get that a lot
多芬舒斯，邪惡企業
在這裏做壞事不會被…
你知道我該把剩下的寫完才對
鴨嘴獸泰瑞，真是驚喜
誒，説到驚喜，不完全是驚喜
反正，讓你看看我最近的成果
我…杜芬舒斯博士又一次
地把東海岸所有的西伯全收集來了
但這一回
我把我的大磁鐵放在了我
的天才磁鐵終結者的旁邊
我要把東邊和西邊的方向調過來
把地球自轉給反過來
我知道我之前試過喇，但是
那是磁鐵終結者
而這是天才磁鐵終結者
我把名字改了點，完全不同的計劃
我知道你想聽我説些悲慘的過去
來解釋我為什麼執意要反轉地球
但我不會説喇，你知道我和你説過
我是説過
Cause when you
grow up in Gimme Some
Your childhood
is less than ideal
So I don't dwell
on how I crawled my way
Out of the gutter
No，I don't
When people
ask me why I…
I'm mean， I'll say
Dum dum
dum dum dum
I stutter
But I'm no
longer a hater
Cause I got an
enabler and an overcomplicated scheme
I get a
couple of checks
Every month
from my ex
So I can finance
my carving regime
And though my
past was a wreck
I won't let it
affect my aspirations
To cosmas hysteria
Cause I'm as
sure as can be
That it's
minus the me
To be the ruler
of the tristate
Golly
請問好了沒有？
我得去學校接我的孩子了
等一下，等畫面暗下來
好了，你可以走了
但是媽媽，我跟佢哋説
他們做的那個很大，我也和你説
這個故事你已經用過喇，是啊
但這次是歌舞劇
飛科和小佛獻上最酷的過山車
開始營業，媽媽
嘿，最酷的過山車
我們有這張海報就可以免費進去嘛？
上次沒有，也許這次該拿以防萬一
嘿，如果説有誰要搭這東西，一定是我
不是你們這些路人甲，照你看…吧
我説了我沒風，我就説了，你沒風
是因為…
我了解你，凱迪斯
沒有瘋子會像你那樣尖叫
如果你想來對奶酪叫的話
我會在乳製品區，你想嗎？
甜心，你想對奶酪叫嗎？
有一點，那就來吧
我希望米卡艾特像我説的一樣好運
我的世界只有這一幕
各位先生女士，男孩女孩
你們所有的人
我為你們呈現今天最壯觀的奇景
在你們的日記上記下來吧
因為將來你們要告訴子孫
説你們今天做了最酷的…
怪想錯
這次還有歌舞伎
抓好，把扣環扣緊去
再放開，往後面拉
哎吔
力哥，你確定安全嗎？
當然啦
Not a written rule
but it's
strongly implied
Permanent taste
of tartar sauce
poured
from a bowl
Scream if
you want to
That's right
Court screwin'
on the interstate
With peanut
butter and other things
我攞到海報喇
然後經濟不景氣
而我有30萬間房子和10000間鄰居
我的會計師要我別理他，我不能那樣
不能因為我邪惡就表示我沒有信用
失誤喇
我简直不能相信
你一路走到服務中心拿線
卻沒有帶電池
你以為電池會從天而降不成嗎？
好吧
那這樣如何？
難道説一百萬也會從天而降嗎？
不會有這種事，我説説都不行嘛？
你太晚喇
夾緊尾巴
無助地看著那難以想像巨大的磁鐵
把東海岸拉過來，然後，讓地球反轉
哎？
看來沒成功
現在我們有一個兩噸重的稀薄以
200哩的時速朝我們衝過來
快，我們得把磁鐵從磁鐵終結者拿下來
不然就太晚喇
是我有問題，還是真的有幻覺？
我總覺得之前也有這樣説過
快啲
我們得把磁鐵從磁鐵終結者拿下來
好吧，怪喇，我們在哪兒？
天啊，他可真恨奶酪
等等，外頭是怎麼回事？
媽媽…
沒用的，我們完喇
你救了我們，鴨嘴獸泰瑞，你又成功喇
又一次的幻覺，你本來在上面
我就説你救了我們，再來…
再來，我就…
我恨你，幻覺
好，我投降，我應該要看什麼？
這不可能
我要去車子那了
它本來在這，而且很大
媽，快走啦，東西會化得
好吧，你以為飛哥和小佛
還會在後院那棵櫻樹下面，是嗎？
是，我是那樣想的
好吧，我們回家，現在
噢，你喺度啊，太陽
帽子真帥啊，伊莎貝拉
有意思，我不記得有這個設計
我確定這是新的
我有時候真擔心你，凱蒂絲
你知道，不和他們回家
凱蒂絲會囉嗦的
嘿，傑洛米，嘿，飛哥，有人要薯條嗎？
不了，我們不用
噢，替我向你姐問好
可麗餅？
哈，蘇西，你要可麗餅嗎？
不，謝謝
「開心見到米普」
「好了，我們回來了，你開心了」
「是」，「看，媽媽」
「我就説他們不在」
「嗨，兒子」，「嗨，媽」
「來吧，凱迪斯，幫我拿東西」
「我們走吧」，「可…
」
嘿，飛哥，太棒喇，太酷喇
太棒喇，可以再嚟一次嘛？
抱歉，每個人只能做一次，太好了
飛哥
你明天想做什麼呢？
你知道他們説的「
carabidium」
咩意思？
「carabidium」
是拉丁文「充實的一天」或者你也
可以用中文説「充實的一天」
是的，你可以
Well we hope you
all enjoyed the show
Hope it was
not anticlimactic
Now there's
something we want you to know
And we don't
wanna sound didactic
But if there's
one thing we can say
I know it
sounds a bit cliche
There's no such
thing as just an ordinary day
好喇，各位，太棒喇，我還想再來一段
先生們、女士們
世界級舞蹈家肯尼奧特將…
謝謝，飛哥
好喇，各位，在最後我們使出全力
像這樣，好嘛？
所有的人，手高舉，歌曲，繼續
五、六、七、八
噢，別這樣，長官
噢，凱爾，我的感覺沒了
長官
我被打斷兩回
你唱得很好啊
噢，是嘛？
是，長官，我有聽見你練習
我平常是有練習
是，就和歌一樣，capitam
拉丁文很有意義，是吧？
是的，長官
好吧，我唱
我的世界是…
噢，拜託